MATTHEW SADECKI

HONOURS APPLIED ECONOMICS MAJOR

Learn more @ matthewsadecki.com

matthewsadecki@gmail.com 647-996-4586 Oakville, ON

SUMMARY

Individual with a background in applied economics and passion to learn and create new technologies. Professional industry experience at BI&I and as a contract developer. Open to new opportunities in full stack web development and/or data analytics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Javascript, Java, C++, C#

Technologies: Git, Node.js, React.js, React-Native, MySQL, Stata, Tableau

Web & Design: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, AJAX, Express is, Balsamiq

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Application Developer Intern, HSB BI&I

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Machine Learning Project | Tech Stack: Python Libraries: pandas, scikit-learn, and seaborne
 - Pre-qualified candidates through phone interviews by asking technical questions related to machine learning and artificial intelligence
 - Selected Kaggle datasets to challenge qualified candidates at IT recruiting event using CRISP-DM process model (with example solutions for staff) to clean data, explore correlations, run machine learning algorithms, and create data visualizations
 - Managed and prioritized multiple concurrent cross-departmental tasks in preparation for recruiting event, and presented complex technical information to non-technical staff
- Progressive Web App Project | Tech Stack: Ionic, React Native, Microsoft Power Apps
 - Developed proof-of-concept apps using popular frameworks to test the viability of required features and presented findings to IT team using matrix style comparisons
 - Performed unit testing on a mobile inspection app used by equipment inspectors

Business Owner, Ivespark Solutions

May 2018 - Present

- Created a cash flow statement with sensitivity analysis to predict future cash flows
- Tutoring | gradementor.com | Tech Stack: Wordpress, CSS, PHP
 - o Tutored K-12 and University students in English, Math, Physics, and Computer Science
- Web Development | getmoreclients.ca | Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Express.js, Balsamiq, Linux
 - Deployed getmoreclients.ca onto DigitalOcean linux server using PuTTY
 - Met with clients to gather requirements, outline schedules, and present wireframes
 - Developed mobile responsive and seo optimized e-commerce websites

Tutor, Medlife Queen's

Sept 2016 - April 2018

• Prepared students for calculus and physics exams in a lecture hall by taking up past exams

PROJECTS

LeadGen | github.com/sadecki558/leadgen | Tech Stack: React-Native, MySQL, FireBase, Socket.io

• LeadGen is a cross platform mobile application that is intended to help users find and chat with potential contractors. LeadGen is a functioning React-Native chat application with live chat.

EDUCATION

B.A. (Honours): Applied Economics, Queen's University

Sept 2015 - April 2020

• Relevant Coursework: Econometrics, Data Analytics, Data Structures, Java, Python, C, Financial Risk Management, Cost-Benefit Analysis, Statistics, Labour Economics, Health Care Economics

Full Stack Web Development, University of Toronto

May 2018 - Nov 2018

- Built frontend and backend of websites (MySQL/MongoDB, Express is, React is, Node is)
- Worked in a team to develop apps while applying version control and issue tracking (Kanban)